<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DH Pitt</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/</link><description>Recent content on DH Pitt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:56:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhpitt.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Neural operators - learning partial differential equations</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/neuraloperator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 13:56:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/neuraloperator/</guid><description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;m working in the Tensor Lab, a joint Caltech-NVIDIA lab working on foundational research at the intersection of AI and physical sciences. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m working on neuraloperator, an open-source software library that allows users to implement the lab&amp;rsquo;s Neural Operator family of machine learning models on physical data governed by partial differential equations (PDEs). PDEs are traditionally solved by methods that model equations as a discrete mesh over a surface.</description></item><item><title>InBrief - using AI to summarize environmental impact statements</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/inbrief/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 11:57:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/inbrief/</guid><description>In affiliation with the University of Michigan, Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning As part of Taubman College&amp;rsquo;s urban technology prototype grant program, I&amp;rsquo;m building a system that uses new large language modeling (LLM) technology to summarize the lengthy environmental impact analyses (EIAs) required of most urban development projects. In the half century since the National Environmental Protection Act (NEPA), these documents have stretched from an average length of 10 pages to over 1,600 pages.</description></item><item><title>My cat</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 13:12:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/cat/</guid><description>Last fall, I adopted a cat. He&amp;rsquo;s really cute and I keep some photos here for his fans.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:17:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/about/</guid><description>I develop machine learning applications that strike a balance between novel research and practical development. I currently work at the Anima AI Lab at Caltech as a Schmidt fellow in software engineering. In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on computer vision and language modeling problems at startups like Granica, Groundlight AI, and Nanotronics Imaging.
I&amp;rsquo;ve previously been fascinated with questions around uncertainty estimation, model calibration and model robustness. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been more excited to use existing but new technologies to build practical products that align with my personal values.</description></item><item><title>Contact me</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:17:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/contact/</guid><description>My email address is david dot h dot pitt at gmail dot com. I generally respond there, but I prefer to chat in real time. You can set up a meeting on my Calendly.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/resume/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 12:17:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/resume/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Robust pose estimation</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/oodcv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 12:00:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/oodcv/</guid><description>I was a finalist in the 2022 European Conference of Computer Vision&amp;rsquo;s Out-of-Distribution Computer Vision (OOD-CV) challenge in the pose estimation track. The challenge focused on the core tendency of machine learning models to learn to recognize uninformative, correlated pattterns instead of semantically useful information. I enrolled in the 6D object pose estimation track because, well, almost nobody else had. To achieve higher results than a standard classification approach, I divided up the pose estimation problem into subproblems based on dimensions of object pose, and also used a proven robustness augmentation that trains models to focus on the shape, rather than texture, of objects in their field of view.</description></item></channel></rss>