<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NLP on DH Pitt</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/tags/nlp/</link><description>Recent content in NLP on DH Pitt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 12:23:07 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dhpitt.com/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Text Bias Inspector</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/aibias/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 12:23:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/aibias/</guid><description>Using HolisticBias as a tool to evaluate bias in a corpus Most work on AI bias is concerned with finding latent biases within a model by evaluating perplexity in generated outputs. I am developing an approach that uses the same method of inquiry to find latent biases within a fine-tuning corpus. By fine-tuning a generative model on a body of text, we can more efficiently study the latent attitudes of a body of work by measuring the impact they have on the demographic biases of the model.</description></item><item><title>InBrief - using AI to summarize environmental impact statements</title><link>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/protogrant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 11:57:12 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.dhpitt.com/work/protogrant/</guid><description>In affiliation with the Taubman College of Architecture and Urban Planning @ University of Michigan As part of Taubman College&amp;rsquo;s urban technology prototype grant program, I&amp;rsquo;m building a system that uses new large language modeling (LLM) technology to summarize the lengthy environmental impact analyses (EIAs) required of most urban development projects. In the half century since the National Environmental Protection Act (NEPA), these documents have stretched from an average length of 10 pages to over 1,600 pages.</description></item></channel></rss>